python = [
{
    "question_number":1,
    "question":"What is the output of print tinylist * 2 if tinylist = [123, 'john']?",
    "options":["[123, 'john', 123, 'john']","[123, 'john'] * 2","Error","None of the above."],
    "answer":"[123, 'john', 123, 'john']"
},
{
    "question_number":2,
    "question":"Which of the following function replaces all occurrences of old substring in string with new string?",
    "options":["replace(old, new [, max])","strip([chars])","swapcase()","title()"],
    "answer":"replace(old, new [, max])"
},
{
    "question_number":3,
    "question":"In Python we can create a popup menu. Select the code to display a popup menu?",
    "options":["Menu.post(250,250)","Menu.post()","Menu.display()","Menu.display_popup(250,250)"],
    "answer":"Menu.post(250,250)"
},
{
    "question_number":4,
    "question":"State ‘Tuples are mutable’?",
    "options":["True","False","May be","Sometimes (Depending upon the condition)"],
    "answer":"False"
},
{
    "question_number":5,
    "question":"What is the value of a?

    a = 4*4-4+4/4",
    "options":["13","5","19","4"],
    "answer":"13"
},
{
    "question_number":6,
    "question":"What will be the output of the following code?

    def f():
       pass
    print(type(f()))",
    "options":["<type 'function '>","<type 'tuple '>","<type 'NoneType '>","<type 'pass '>"],
    "answer":"<type 'NoneType '>"
},
{
    "question_number":7,
    "question":"What is the output of print list if list = [ 'abcd', 786 , 2.23, 'john', 70.2 ]?",
    "options":["[ 'abcd', 786 , 2.23, 'john', 70.2 ]","list","Error","None of the above."],
    "answer":"[ 'abcd', 786 , 2.23, 'john', 70.2 ]"
},
{
    "question_number":8,
    "question":"What is the output of print str[2:] if str = 'Hello World!'?",
    "options":["llo World!","H","llo","None of the above."],
    "answer":"llo World!"
},
{
    "question_number":9,
    "question":"Which of the following function randomizes the items of a list in place?",
    "options":["shuffle(lst)","capitalize()","isalnum()","isdigit()"],
    "answer":"shuffle(lst)"
},
{
    "question_number":10,
    "question":"Which of the following data types is not supported in python?",
    "options":["Numbers","String","List","Slice"],
    "answer":"Slice"
},
{
    "question_number":11,
    "question":"What is the following function inserts an object at given index in a list?",
    "options":["list.index(obj)","list.insert(index, obj)","list.pop(obj=list[-1])","list.remove(obj)"],
    "answer":"list.insert(index, obj)"
},
{
    "question_number":12,
    "question":"What is output for −

    ' ' in 'python' ?",
    "options":["'python'","False","Name error","True"],
    "answer":"True"
},
{
    "question_number":13,
    "question":"What is output of following code −

    def func(x, ans):
       if(x==0):
          return 0
       else: 
          return func(x-1, x+ans) 
    print(func(2,0))",
    "options":["0","1","2","3"],
    "answer":"0"
},
{
    "question_number":14,
    "question":"Which of the following data types is not supported in python?",
    "options":["Tuple","Dictionary","Generics","List"],
    "answer":"Generics"
},
{
    "question_number":15,
    "question":"Which way among them is used to create an event loop ?",
    "options":["Window.eventloop()","Window.mainloop()","Window.loop()","Eventloop.window()"],
    "answer":"Window.mainloop()"
},
{
    "question_number":16,
    "question":"What is the range of method ‘random.random()’?",
    "options":["(0.0 , 1.0)","(0.0 , 1.0]","[0.0, 1.0)","[0.0 , 1.0]"],
    "answer":"[0.0, 1.0)"
},
{
    "question_number":17,
    "question":"Select the correct option to draw a rectangle centred at 50,50 with width and height as 50, 70 respectively.",
    "options":["Canvas.create_rect(50,50,50,70)","Canvas.create_rect(50,70,50,50)","Canvas.create_rectangle(50,50,50,70)","Tkinter.create_rect(50,50,50,70)"],
    "answer":"Canvas.create_rectangle(50,50,50,70)"
},
{
    "question_number":18,
    "question":"Suppose you are given a set(s1={1,2,3}) then what is the output for the code −

    2 * s1?",
    "options":["(1,1,2,2,3,3)","[1,1,2,2,3,3]","Illegal","(1,2,3,1,2,3)"],
    "answer":"Illegal"
},
{
    "question_number":19,
    "question":"What is output of following code −

    s = ''mnopqr ''
    i = ''m ''
    while i in s:
       print('i', end= '' '')",
    "options":["i i i i i i i i……..","m m m m m …..","m n o p q r","no output"],
    "answer":"i i i i i i i i…….."
},
{
    "question_number":20,
    "question":"Which among them is incorrect for set s={100,101,102,103}",
    "options":["Len(s)","Sum(s)","Print(s[3])","Max(s)"],
    "answer":"Print(s[3])"
}
]